Samyuktha Mahesh

Collaborated in a 5-person capstone project team for the analysis of Medicare Healthcare Fraudulent Activities. Experienced Machine Learning Data Associate II, prepared to provide solutions to the business problems by means of data analysis, visualization and modelling.

Personal Info

Email

samyukthamahesh@gmail.com

GitHub

https://github.com/SamyukthaMahesh

Linkadln

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samyuktha-mahesh/

Website

https://samyukthamahesh.github.io/samyuktha_mahesh/

Certificates

Business English Certificate Preliminary

Pass with Merit

Date of Issue: 31/05/2013

Skills

Python

Tableau

MySQL

Building business model hypothesis

Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning Algorithms

Jira/confluence

Languages

English

Tamil

Hindi

Hobby

- Reading Analytics Vidhya ,KDNuggets and Medium
- · Playing Table Tennis

Projects

2020-02 - 2020-03

Fraud Detection in Medicare Healthcare Insurance

The goal of the project is to save enormous amount of money from frauds which would aid those who are in real need. Using optimization techniques, precision of 95% was achieved which helped to obtain the Total Savings.

V

Work History

2018-04 - 2019-01

Machine Learning Data Associate II

Amazon Development Center, Chennai, India

- Upgraded to Quality Assurance Trainee to test Alexa Devices across Pan India
- Identified bugs, reported professionally and in timely manner
- Recognised features for the improvement of Alexa's performances.
- Supported in designing a new website for process improvement.

2016-08 - 2018-03

Machine Learning Data Associate I

Amazon Development Center, Chennai, India

- Annotated all the data that comes in the process with minimal direction and with high quality.
- Mentored an entire batch of 15 members for annotation trainees and spearheaded a batch of 3 members.
- Built and maintained a website by collating all daily updates for easy reference. It increased the annotation quality and reduced the time for referencing.
- Transcribed high priority and difficult deliverables with minimal direction.
- Created a guide document for one of the complicated transcription and it's ways which helped in improving the transcription quality by 5%. The guide also helped to train the trainees for the queue.
- Trained by the Automation Technical lead and delivered a Kaizen Project to production with the annualized benefit of USD \$4757 for the team.

Education

2020-08 - 2020-04

Great Lakes Institute of Mangement, Chennai,India

Post Graduate Program, Data Science

2012-07 - 2016-04

Anna University, Chennai

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication Engineering